<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>sytzez</title>
    <link>https://sytzez.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on sytzez</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://sytzez.com/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sytzez.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How I manage my work like a boss</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/how-i-manage-my-work-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/how-i-manage-my-work-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>If you have deadlines on top of people asking you to do stuff ASAP, on top of issues that need to be fixed immediately, on top of many meetings throughout the day, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to lose track of your to do list or prioritise the wrong things.
My to do list method has helped me keep an overview of everything I need to do. It&amp;rsquo;s low overhead once you get used to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch for a new programming language: Part 2</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/sketch-for-a-new-programming-language-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/sketch-for-a-new-programming-language-2/</guid>
      <description>A solution to inheritance I&amp;rsquo;ve had some more thought about my programming language &amp;ldquo;Compost&amp;rdquo;. It has a solution to the old problems of object oriented programming, mainly class inheritance.
One of the problems class inheritance tries to solve is repeated code between classes, by creating a superclass that contains all the common methods, which subclasses inherit from it. But class inheritance comes with its own problems, and has gotten out of favor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketch for a new programming language</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/sketch-for-a-new-programming-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/sketch-for-a-new-programming-language/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m coming up with the spec of a new programming language. Working title: &amp;ldquo;Compost&amp;rdquo;. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry, it&amp;rsquo;s just for fun. For now this is just a first sketch of the ideas I had today. They are subject to change.
The main idea of the language is ultimate composability and recomposability. It forces the programmer to think in terms of the minimum amount of dependencies required for each part of the code, and makes each part as reusable as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Composing &#39;Ouverture&#39;</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/composing-ouverture/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/composing-ouverture/</guid>
      <description>In this blog I will show how I composed the baroque style piece &amp;lsquo;Ouverture&amp;rsquo; starting with simple, strict two-voice counterpoint, and then embellishing that into a fuller baroque style.
Most of the material is derived from a single melody which is varied using augmentation, fragmentation, inversion and embellishment.
In the sheet music for this blog I&amp;rsquo;ve added numbers in between the two staves indicating the intervals between the top and the bottom voice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Responsive sheet music in Hugo using MusicXML</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/responsive-sheet-music-in-hugo-using-music-xml/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/responsive-sheet-music-in-hugo-using-music-xml/</guid>
      <description>In this blog I will explain how to easily add sheet music to your site, such as the example below. Note how the division of the bars adjusts when you shrink your screen width, it&amp;rsquo;s truly responsive!
Introduction When writing blogs about music, you might want to render snippets of music notation in between paragraphs of text. I will show you how to easily embed MusicXML content within your Hugo posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modes of Solfege</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/modes-of-solfege/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/modes-of-solfege/</guid>
      <description>The two skills of solfege Solfege, in its fullest sense, is the art of translating musical ideas from one representation into another. It teaches the skill of, on the one hand, recognising music in all its forms and, on the other hand, reproducing music in another form.
graph RL A[Music] subgraph solfege B[Recognition] C[Reproduction] end A---B C---A Music&amp;rsquo;s primary medium is sound. Another common medium is music notation, which is written using special musical symbols known as &amp;rsquo;notes&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Initial post</title>
      <link>https://sytzez.com/blog/initial-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://sytzez.com/blog/initial-post/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a while about starting a blog to get various ideas out there in the world, whether they be about programming, music or other things. Getting content out there on &amp;rsquo;the web&amp;rsquo; might help me promote the things I&amp;rsquo;m doing, attract likeminded people or people that can help me in my endeavours, and it can help me hold myself accountable to the ideas I get and the goals I set for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
